<PropertyList>
    <title>Perlan2</title>
    <key>
        <name>Ctrl-w</name>
        <desc>Place winch in front of aircraft</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>W</name>
        <desc>Increase winch speed</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>w</name>
        <desc>Decrease winch speed</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>Ctrl-o</name>
        <desc>Find aircraft for aerotow</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>o</name>
        <desc>Open aerotow and winch hooks. This releases the cable if one is attached.</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>k/j</name>
        <desc>speedbrakes out/in</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>B , .</name>
        <desc>Parking Brake, brakes</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>F2</name>
        <desc>Drouge Parachute</desc>
    </key>
    <key>
        <name>&lt;</name>
        <desc>Change right, left and center pilot view</desc>
    </key>
    
    <text>
      
Perlan2 Stratospheric Glider by Herbert Wagner 09/2017-2018

    === General Help ===
    
     - You can take off using a winch or use another aircraft as an aerotow.
     - The winch / aerotow cable can be released with the "o" key or using button 1 of the (first) joystick.

    === Winch Takeoff Procedure ===

     - Retract speed brake
     - Set trim just forward of the middle position.
     - Press 'Ctrl-w' to place winch.
     - Press 'Shift-w' to start winch and take up cable slack.
     - When the glider starts moving, press 'Shift-w' several times to accelerate the winch
       (up to full speed).
     - Keep the wings level with the aileron and the glider going in a straight line with the rudder.
       Keep elevator centered, the glider will lift off and rotate by automatically as long as the trim is set
       correctly.
       Once the established in the climb, you can pull back on the stick slightly to increase climb rate.
     - Control the winch speed throughout the entire launch. 'Shift-w' makes the winch run faster,
       'w' makes it run slower.
       Try to maintain constant force on the cable, you will need to gradually slow down the winch
       as glider climbs.
     - When the glider reaches the top of the launch, close winch throttle to 5% and press 'o'
       to release the cable.

    === Aerotow Takeoff Procedure ===

      - Set maximum speed brake
      - Place another aerotow aircraft in front of your glider (multi-player).
      - Press 'Ctrl-o' to hook to the aerotow.
      - Ask the other aircraft to take off :).
      - Keep wings level and follow the aircraft until after takeoff.
      - The glider should lift off before the tug, stay close to the ground until the tug starts climbing.
      - Slowly reduce the speedbrake
      - When at appropriate alitude, press 'o' to release the cable.

    === Ground handling ===

    This aircraft has some features to help with ground handling:

      - Enable wing holder: the aircraft gets levelled around the x-axis as if
        someone was holding your wing.
      - Enable ground handling: controls are modified to help move the glider around
        on the ground:
        1. All rudder inputs will make the glider turn, as if someone was pulling on the wingtip.
        2. All throttle inputs cause the glider to taxi, as if someone (or a car) was pulling or pushing it.
      - When exceeding a given speed of 15 kts assisting gears will be reset to off (e.g. on takeoff), ground handling will become inactive at 20kts.

    When there is somebody with a follow-me around, you can connect to it by pressing Ctrl+o
    (release: Ctrl+shift+o) so he can carry you around the airport
    or even tow you into the air! (also check the Aerotow Settings therefore).

    === Descending from high altitide ===
    
    Use the drog parachute (F2) or the switch in the panel to reduce speed when descending.
    
    === Realistic weather settings ===
    
    For realistic Weather go to Weather Conditions:
    Fair weather -- Detailed Weather -- Advanced Settings
    Tile Selection Mode: realistic
    Terrain Effects and Terrain Presampling: on
    Wind Model: aloft interpolated

    Check your wind configuration:
    FL0 260 12
    FL50 262 16
    FL100 264 20
    FL180 265 28
    FL240 269 39
    FL300 273 47
    FL340 278 54
    FL390 271 59
    FL450 275 68

    The towing will start a Cessna 177 with sound at the apron,
    it then will go to the startpoint for towing on the east side of the runway.
    Use the speedbrakes to compensate for the elastic rope at start-up.
    
    === Scenery features ===
    
    There are two sceneries implemented, go to the wavelift folder and follow the instructions in the readme.txt file.
    </text>
</PropertyList>
